<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2019 Dariusz Bogdanski <dariuszb@me.com> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <metadata_license>Unlicense</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Unlicense</project_license>
  <name>Rclone Browser</name>
  <summary>Simple cross platfrom GUI for rclone command line.</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Rclone Browser is a cross-platform Qt5 GUI for Rclone, a command line tool to synchronize (and mount) files from remote cloud storage services like Google Drive, OneDrive, Nextcloud, Dropbox, Amazon Drive and S3, Mega, and others. Use it to copy a file from one cloud storage service to another, from a cloud storage to your system or the other way around, and to mount some cloud storage on your system with a single click.</p>
    <p> - Allows to browse and modify any rclone remote, including encrypted ones</p>
    <p> - Uses same configuration file as rclone, no extra configuration required</p>
    <p> - Supports custom location and encryption for .rclone.conf configuration file</p>
    <p> - Simultaneously navigate multiple repositories in separate tabs</p>
    <p> - Lists files hierarchically with file name, size and modify date</p>
    <p> - All rclone commands are executed asynchronously, no freezing GUI</p>
    <p> - File hierarchy is lazily cached in memory, for faster traversal of folders</p>
    <p> - Allows to upload, download, create new folders, rename or delete files and folders</p>
    <p> - Allows to calculate size of folder, export list of files and copy rclone command to clipboard</p>
    <p> - Can process multiple upload or download jobs in background</p>
    <p> - Drag and drop support for dragging files from local file explorer for uploading</p>
    <p> - Streaming media files for playback in player like vlc or similar</p>
    <p> - Mount and unmount folders on macOS, GNU/Linux and Windows (for Windows requires winfsp)</p>
    <p> - Optionally minimizes to tray, with notifications when upload/download finishes</p>
    <p> - Supports portable mode (create .ini file next to executable with same name), rclone and .rclone.conf path now can be relative to executable</p>
    <p> - Supports drive-shared-with-me (Google Drive specific)</p>
    <p> - For remotes supporting public link sharing has an option (right-click menu) to fetch it</p>
    <p> - Supports tasks. Created jobs can be saved and run or edited later.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/wiki/images/IMGdefault.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/wiki/images/IMGtransfer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/issues/</url>
  <url type="faq">https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/wiki</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/kapitainsky/RcloneBrowser/issues/</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2019-10-30" />
  </releases>
  <developer_name>Dariusz Bogdanski and contributors</developer_name>
  <update_contact>dariuszb@me.com</update_contact>
  <provides>
    <binary>rclone-browser</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
